(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
未練レコード / 歌：ときのそら / 動画：チーム友人A
Miren Record / Vocals: Tokino Sora / Video: Team Yuujin A
こんあづきー！みんな、AZKi生誕祭に来てくれてありがとう！
Kon-AZKi! Everyone, thank you for coming to AZKi's Birthday Celebration!
一緒に盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get excited together!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
そう　見つけた　この先だけの世界を
So, I found it, a world just for the future
止まりかけていた時を進めるための
To advance the time that had almost stopped
こんなはずなかった　ふともれた言葉さえ
Even the words that accidentally leaked out, that shouldn't have been
あんな日も良かった　そう思える君がいるよ
You are here, making me think those days were good too
消えかけても　見えなくても　ここに私はいる
Even if I fade, even if I'm invisible, I am here
暗闇の世界さえ　越えてく光を
A light that crosses even the world of darkness
間違っても　無くなっても　僕の選ぶ世界
Even if I'm wrong, even if it's gone, the world I choose
思い描いた花じゃなくたって　この種咲かすよ
Even if it's not the flower I imagined, I'll make this seed bloom
みんな、お祝いの声、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for the celebratory voices!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
ああ　見つけた　失くしかけてた僕の座標
Ah, I found it, my coordinates that I almost lost
エンドロールには早すぎると気付いた
I realized it's too early for the end credits
僕だけじゃないんだ　気付けば側にいたんだ
I'm not the only one, I realized you were by my side
足跡は続く　ほら聞こえる次の音が
The footprints continue, look, I can hear the next sound
届かなくても　憧れを背に少しだけ追い越した
Even if I can't reach, with longing on my back, I overtook just a little
花と咲くその日まで　思いを歌うよ
Until the day it blooms as a flower, I'll sing my feelings
途切れた糸　また繋がるそんな世界があるよ
Broken threads, reconnected again, such a world exists
次の夜空に光る星々に希望を託そう
Let's entrust hope to the stars shining in the next night sky
こんな世界
Such a world
こんな未来
Such a future
僕らの地図になかった
Was not on our map
約束できないよ
I can't promise you
こんな素敵な未来
Such a wonderful future
想像できないから
Because I can't even imagine it
消えかけても
Even if it fades
見えなくても
Even if it can't be seen
何度くじけても
No matter how many times I falter
足跡の伸びる先
Where the footprints lead
未来が続くよ
The future continues
そう 間違っても
Yes, even if we make mistakes
なくなっても
Even if things are lost
何度でも作ろう
Let's create it again and again
行く先をなくしても
Even if we lose our way
君となら探せるよ
I can find it if I'm with you
上書きの地図
Spread out
お広げて
The overwritten map
僕らの世界で
In our world
君が歩くこの道は
This path you walk
いくつもの思い出を書き連ねてゆく
Will accumulate many memories
変わることを恐れず
Without fearing change
不器用でも君だけの道を歩み
Even if awkward, walk your own path
覚えているよ いつか願った奇跡
I remember the miracle I once wished for
憧れを詰め込んだ 答えのない旅路の途中
In the middle of an answerless journey packed with longings
描いてた物語とは違うけど
It's different from the story I envisioned
あの時の君に誇れる今日がある
But today I can be proud of to the you of that time
何度も悩んで
Worried many times
何度も悔んだ
Regretted many times
これまでの全てが今に繋がる
Everything up until now leads to the present
だから始めよう
So let's begin
またここから
Again from here
僕だけが描き続ける 夢のようなストーリー
A dream-like story that only I continue to draw
あの日の君に伝える言葉 それは
The words I'll tell the you of that day, they are
大丈夫 だからさ
"It's okay," so
前を向いて進んで
Look forward and move on
君が出会うこれからが
From now on, what you encounter
想像もない物語の初めのページ
Is the first page of an unimaginable story
おとぎ話みたいな
Like a fairy tale
出会いとか別れがいくつもあるから
Because there are many encounters and farewells
僕だけが知ってる答えを
The answer that only I know
ずっと探し続けて迷ってたんだ
I've been searching for it and wandering for a long time
辿り着いた今日がこんなに
Today that I finally reached is so
愛しくて切なく
Dear and bittersweet
ここにいる意味を見つけたよ
I've found the meaning of being here
あの日から変わらない想いがあるから
Because there's a feeling that hasn't changed since that day
その涙忘れないで 無駄じゃないから
Don't forget those tears, because they're not in vain
何度も転んで
Fallen many times
何度も間違えて
Mistaken many times
でもそれが君だけの道を開く
But that will open your own path
だからありがとうと伝えさせて
So let me say thank you
その一歩踏み出した勇気が始まり
That courage of taking the first step is the beginning
行き着く先にどんな壁があっても
No matter what walls are at the destination
乗り越えてゆけるから信じて
Believe that we can overcome them
今の僕と君が出会ったら
If the current me and you were to meet
どんな言葉をかけてくれる?
What kind of words would you give me?
君が想う未来とは違うけど
It's different from the future you imagined
それでも良かったと言えるから
But I can say that it was good nonetheless
Because I can say it was all worth it
描いていた物語とは違うけど
It's different from the story I had pictured
あの時の君に誇れる今日がある
But today is a day I can show off with pride to my past self
何度も流した涙はきっと
The tears I've shed countless times
これからの宝物に変わるから
Will surely turn into treasures for the future
ホロライブへ移籍しました！
Moved to hololive!
あの日から変わらない思いがあるから
Because I have feelings that haven't changed since that day
その勇気忘れないで光になるから
Don't forget that courage, it will become a light
何度も転んで それでも走って
Falling down over and over, but still running on
君だけが描き続ける物語
A story that only you can keep on drawing
だから ありがとうと伝えたくて
That's why I wanted to say thank you
これまでの出来事が道しるべになり
Everything that's happened until now becomes a guidepost
君がいたから今の僕があるよ
I am who I am today because you were there
どれほど変わっても一つだけのストーリー
No matter how much things change, it's the one and only story
ねえ またここから描き始めてゆくんだ
Hey, let's start drawing again from here
こんあずきー！
Kon-AZKi!
AZKiでーす！
It's AZKi!
えー、今日は、AZKi生誕祭ライブに来てくれて、ありがとうございます。
Um, thank you all for coming to the AZKi Birthday Celebration Live today.
えー、1曲目、2曲目は、オーバーライトと、ExistLogを歌わせていただきました。
Um, for the first and second songs, I sang "Overwrite" and "ExistLog."
はい。ということで、えー、やってまいりました。
Yes. And so, the time has finally come.
本当に、久々のライブでめちゃくちゃ緊張してるんですけれども、
It's been a long time since my last live, so I'm really nervous,
今日は全編、生ライブで、お届けしていきたいと思います。
but I'll be performing the entire set live today.
今日のハッシュタグはですね、
The hashtag for today is...
えー、こちらこちらこちらこちら、こちら、#AZKi生誕祭2022 で、
um, this one right here, #AZKiSeitansai2022,
ぜひ、呟いてくれたら嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you could tweet using it.
はい。今日はね、本当に、ちょっと、あの、ゲストもいるし、
Yes. Today, well, we have guests,
あのね、いろんな発表もありますので、
and there are various announcements to make,
もうね、どんどん、どんどん、今日は歌っていきたいと思います。
so I'm going to keep on singing today.
一緒に盛り上がってくれますかー！
Are you ready to get hyped with me?!
いえーい！
Yay!
ということで、次の曲、聴いてください。
And so, please listen to the next song.
『画面の中の君が好き』。
"Gamen no Naka no Kimi ga Suki."
君を初めて見つけた時
When I first found you
なぜか心揺さぶられたんだ
My heart was shaken for some reason
作りものに命を宿す
Breathing life into a creation
君の輝きは本物だった
Your brilliance was the real deal
楽しそうな君は素敵だった
You looked so wonderful having fun
画面の中の君が好き
I love you, the one inside the screen
その化粧した君の顔が
With that face of yours made up
ただ君が変われたらいい
I just hope that you could change
本当の君と実は違うとしても
Even if you're actually different from the real you
新しい扉を開けて
Open a new door
息をしようよ
And let's take a breath
嘘も本当も関係ないから
Because lies or truth don't matter
息をしている瞬間を僕ら見届けたいんだ
We want to witness the moments you're breathing
君が好きだから
Because I love you
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
もしも君が生きづらいなら
If you find it hard to live
好きな顔と服を着てもいい
It's okay to wear the face and clothes you like
もしも君が辞めたくなっても
Even if you feel like quitting
僕らは止めたりしないからさ
We won't try to stop you
生きやすい場所を探せばいい
Just look for a place where it's easier to live
君の言葉が僕に刺さった
Your words pierced through me
君の歌に僕は揺さぶられた
I was shaken by your song
君の配信に僕は夢中になった
I became captivated by your streams
画面の中の君が僕を救ってくれた
You, inside the screen, saved me
いつか画面の外へいなくなっても
Even if you disappear from the outside of the screen one day
画面の中にいた君のこと
The you that was inside the screen...
君自身が好きでいてくれてたら嬉しいな
I'd be happy if you could love that version of yourself
ただ君が変われたらいい
I just hope that you could change
本当の君と実は違うとしても
Even if you're actually different from the real you
新しい扉を開けた君の軌跡は
The trail you left by opening a new door
嘘も本当も抱きしめてよ
Embrace it all, both the lies and the truth
君にとってこの場所が生きる場所
For you, this is the place to live
手になれたなら
If I could become those hands
僕は幸せだ
I would be happy
幸せだから
Because I'm happy
La la la...
みんなも一緒に手を振ってー！
Everyone, wave your hands together!
La la la...
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
猫になって甘やかされたい
I want to be a cat and be pampered
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to be a cat and be loved
猫になってお昼寝させて
Let me take a nap as a cat
起きたら100万登録いってないかな
I wonder if I'll reach 1 million subs when I wake up
猫ならばいける
If I'm a cat, I can do it!
みんなニャニャ言っておくれ
Everyone, please say "nya nya"
ニャー！ニャー！ ニャー！ニャー！
Nya! Nya! Nya! Nya!
忙しくてもちゃんとおはツイしなくちゃ
Even if I'm busy, I have to do my morning tweet properly
下書き悩んで3時間経って
3 hours passed while worrying over the draft
完璧な140字送信ミスってデリート
Messing up the sending of the perfect 140 characters and deleting it
心が折れる日曜日
Sunday when my heart breaks
休みなしで歌い続ける そんなのへっちゃら余裕だぜ
Continuing to sing without rest, that's no problem at all, a piece of cake
みんなと一緒なら大丈夫
As long as I'm with everyone, it's fine
だから追いよろしくね 奉仕的な甘やかしで
So please follow me, with a serving of service-like pampering
配信毎回全編見てね
Please watch the full stream every time
でも今日はやばい
But today is bad
本当に眠い
I'm really sleepy
こんな私もちゃんと見てほしい
I want you to look at me like this too
無償の愛がほしい
I want unconditional love
だから猫になって甘やかされたい
So I want to be a cat and be pampered
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to be a cat and be loved
猫になってお昼寝させて
Let me take a nap as a cat
起きたら100万登録だ
I'll have 1 million subs when I wake up
猫になって輝きたいの
I want to be a cat and shine
猫になって買いたくするよ
I'll make you want to buy by becoming a cat
もっと君に伝わりますように
I hope it reaches you more
猫ならばいける
If I'm a cat, I can do it!
ニャー！ニャー！ ニャー！ニャー！
Nya! Nya! Nya! Nya!
お散歩してたら公園で
While taking a walk in the park
かわいいワンちゃん見つけたよ
I found a cute doggy
撫でようとしたら吠えられた
When I tried to pet it, it barked at me
やっぱ猫になりたい
I really want to be a cat after all
でもどうすればいい
But what should I do?
猫のなりかた
How to become a cat
ググっても出ない ホント教えてほしい
It doesn't come up even if I Google it, I want you to tell me the truth
スクショ作ってほしい
I want you to take screenshots
だから猫になって抱きしめられたい
So I want to be a cat and be hugged
猫になってなでなでしてよ
Become a cat and pet me
猫になってエサを与えて
Become a cat and feed me
山盛りちゅーるよろしくね
A mountain of Churu, please
猫になって恋してたいの
I want to be a cat and be in love
猫になって笑い合おうよ
Let's laugh together as cats
もっとみんな猫になろうよ
Let's all become cats more
ニャー！ニャー！ ニャー！ニャー！
Nya! Nya! Nya! Nya!
本当やばい
Really bad
起きたら12時
Woke up and it was 12:00
タイムリミット来てるでももう仕方ない
The time limit is here but there's no choice
逆に二度寝しましょう
On the contrary, let's sleep in twice
だから
So...
だから猫になって甘やかされたい
So I want to be a cat and be pampered
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to be a cat and be loved
猫になってお昼寝させて
Let me take a nap as a cat
起きたら100万登録だ
I'll have 1 million subs when I wake up
猫になって輝きたいの
I want to be a cat and shine
猫になって買いたくするよ
I'll make you want to buy by becoming a cat
もっと君に伝わりますように
I hope it reaches you more
もっともっと猫になって甘やかされたい
More and more, I want to be a cat and be pampered
ずっと
Forever
猫になって抱きしめられたい
I want to be a cat and be hugged
もっと
More
猫になって恋してたいの
I want to be a cat and be in love
猫になって笑い合おうよ
Let's laugh together as cats
もっとみんな猫になろうよ
Let's all become cats more
猫ならばいける
If I'm a cat, I can do it!
君とならばいける
If I'm with you, I can do it!
ニャー！ニャー！ ニャー！ニャー！
Nya! Nya! Nya! Nya!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
Movie: Ryuji
みんなで行くよ！
Everyone, let's go!
にゃー！
Meow!
というわけで、2曲連続でお届けしました！
And so, I've just performed two songs in a row!
みんな、一緒ににゃにゃしてくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you everyone for meowing along with me!
はい、画面の中の君が好きと、
Yes, I performed 'I love you inside the screen' and,
えー、そして猫ならいけるの2曲をお届けしました！
uh, 'If you're a cat, you can do it'!
はい。ちょっと飛ばしてきたので、お水を飲んでもいいですか？
Yes. I've been going a bit fast, so can I drink some water?
お水補給、お水補給します。
Hydration, I'll hydrate with some water.
よし！
Alright!
はい、皆さん、それではね、もうお待ちかねだと思います。
Yes, everyone, well then, I think you've all been waiting.
ゲスト、ここでお呼びしたいと思います！
I'd like to call out the guest here!
いいですか？皆さん準備いいですか？
Is it okay? Is everyone ready?
それでは、
Well then,
そらちゃーん！
Sora-chaaan!
おめでとー！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！そらちゃんが来てくれました！
Thank you! Sora-chan is here!
あずあず、おめでとー！
AZKi, congratulations!
ありがとう！今日来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you for coming today!
よろしくお願いします、そらちゃんです！
Please welcome her, it's Sora-chan!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look after me!
あ、そらちゃん、アイドル衣装じゃないですか！
Ah, Sora-chan, you're in your idol costume, aren't you!
そうなんですよ！
That's right!
じゃあ私もアイドル衣装に着替えてきていいかな？
Then, can I go change into my idol costume too?
いいよー！
Sure!
行ってくるぜー！見ててねー！
I'm off! Watch me!
いってらっしゃーい！
Have a safe trip!
よいしょ、よいしょ。アイドル衣装、どんな衣装だと思う？
Heave-ho, heave-ho. Idol costume, what kind of costume do you think it is?
みんな、知ってるかな？どんな衣装かなー。
Everyone, do you know? What kind of costume is it?
知ってると思うんだよな。よいしょ、よいしょ。
I think you know. Heave-ho, heave-ho.
お、もう準備ができたみたいですね。
Oh, it looks like she's ready.
そうなんですよ、もう早着替えのプロなんで。
That's right, she's a pro at quick changes.
あずちー！はい！
Azuchi-! Yes!
やったー！黒！
Yay! Black!
そう、黒と白でね、アイドル衣装で今日はそらちゃんと歌っていきたいと
Yes, in black and white, I want to sing with Sora-chan in idol costumes today
あ、ピース、みんな、
Ah, peace, everyone,
イエーイ、
Yay,
イエーイ！
Yay!
いい、いい、いい、いい！
Good, good, good, good!
今日はね、この2人が揃ったということで、あの曲をやりましょう！
Since the two of us are together today, let's do *that* song!
はい！
Yes!
お水飲もう。
Let's drink water.
お水飲んで。
Drink water.
お水飲んでね。
Drink water, okay?
お水飲んどこう。
Let's drink water.
お、あれ？もう一回どうぞ。
Oh, huh? Go ahead, one more time.
お水はいくら飲んでもいいものですから。
You can never drink too much water.
いいものですから。
It's good for you.
はい、みんなもしっかり水分補給しながら見てね。
Yes, everyone, please watch while staying hydrated too.
そうだね、毎日暑いからね。
That's right, it's hot every day.
そうだね。
Yeah.
はい、ということで、一緒にタイトルコールしてくれますか？
Yes, so, will you do the title call with me?
はい！
Yes!
では、行きたいと思います！
Then, let's go!
はい！
Yes!
せーの、
Ready, go,
紅藍クロニクル！
Kurenai Chronicle!
紅藍クロニクル
Kurenai Chronicle
作詞：AZKi 編曲：RD-Sounds
Lyrics: AZKi  Arrangement: RD-Sounds
雲の間に隠れた　無数の星よ
Countless stars hidden between the clouds
今君は　どこで輝いているんだろう
Where are you shining now?
荒野を彷徨う　無数の旅は
Countless journeys wandering the wasteland
今僕を　どこかへ連れていくよう
Seem to take me somewhere now
僕らが出会うため
For us to meet
世界中で
throughout the world
共に生きてくため
For us to live together
運命の切り札
the trump card of fate
放って、この空の先
Emit it, beyond this sky
どこまでも
to anywhere
呼び覚ませ　心にあるものを
Awaken what is in your heart
殻を破り　飛び立つよ　紅に
Breaking the shell, I'll fly away into the crimson
果てない青が　混ざり合う　煌めく光になれ
The endless blue mixes in, become a sparkling light
悲しさよ　寂しさよ　雨打たれても
Sadness, loneliness, even if struck by rain
辿り着く音　確かなメロディ　それはきっと嘘じゃないよ
The sound reached, a certain melody, that surely isn't a lie
ここで　いつまでも
Here, forever
いつまでも
forever
ふたり歌い合おう
let's sing together
誰にも見せない　弱さがほら
Look, the weakness I show to no one
こぼれては　力に変わっていくから
spills over and turns into strength
誰かを信じる　勇気はもう
If I shake off the courage
振り切って　前へと進むなら
to believe in someone and move forward
打ち砕け
Smash it to pieces
僕らの存在はバーチャルで
Our existence is virtual
代わりなんていないリアルなんだ
But it's real, with no substitute
だってこの魂は本物だ
Because this soul is the real thing
打ち砕け、理不尽も常識も
Smash it to pieces: the injustice, the common sense
壁を越えて　高らかに
Go beyond the walls, loud and clear
果てない赤、胸を貫く脈打つ血汐になれ
Endless red, become the pulsing lifeblood
that pierces my chest
愛しさや切なさを覚えていくの
I'm coming to know love and sorrow
創り出すほど確かなハーモニー
The harmony that becomes more certain
the more we create
これは生きた証だから　聴かせてよ
Because this is proof of having lived,
let me hear you
聴かせてよ　ふたり歌いあう
Let me hear you, two voices singing together
美しく燃え上がる炎よ
O flames, burning up beautifully
あぁ、御空へと咲く花よ
Ah, O flower blooming towards the great sky
互いに目を見合わせて
Exchanging glances with each other
互いに手と手重ねて
Placing our hands on top of each other's
共に歌え　叫べ　今
Sing together, shout together, now
果てない藍、僕ら貫く消えない記憶になれ
Endless indigo, become the indelible memories
that pierce us
愛しさや切なさは抱えたままで
While still holding onto love and sorrow
辿り着くほど確かなメロディ
The melody that becomes more certain
the further we go
これは生きた証だから！今も聴こえている？
Because this is proof of having lived!
Can you hear it even now?
聴こえてるよ！ふたりだけの歌だよ
I can hear it! It's a song just for the two of us
次の曲はそらちゃんの、未練レコードを一緒に歌いたいと思います！
For the next song, I'd like us to sing
Sora-chan's 'Miren Record' together!
やったー！
Yay!
盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get pumped up!
せーの！
Ready, set, go!
まだほんのちょっと未練がましく
Still feeling just a little bit of regret
君が好きだった歌をかけてみる
I try playing the song you used to like
重たくなった針は時計回り
The hands that have grown heavy turn clockwise
ただ空回った歯車がひとつ
Just a single gear spinning in vain
あーだ　こーだ　ストラトの
Saying this and that, the Strat's...
泣き声が響いた
Cry echoed out
私の名前なんて忘れていいよ
You can just forget about my name
ひらり舞い散る花のように
Like a flower fluttering down
だけどいつかこの歌を聴く時は
But someday, when you hear this song...
ねえ、隣に誰かがいたこと思い出して
Hey, remember that someone was by your side
お幸せに　なんて最後の言葉
Saying 'Be happy' as your final words
無理につっぱねて笑ってみたけど
I tried to force a laugh and push it away
私と付き合っていた頃よりも
More than the time you were with me...
幸せになって欲しくはないのよ
I don't want you to be happy
あーだ　こーだ　バスドラが
Saying this and that, the bass drum...
心を蹴飛ばした
Kicked my heart
初デートの写真もペアリングも
The photo of our first date and the matching rings...
簡単に捨てられたらいいのに
I wish I could just throw them away easily
胸に刻まれた歌声のせいで
Because of the singing voice etched into my heart
また君の笑顔思い出してしまうんだ
I end up remembering your smile again
私の泣き声が響いた
My crying voice echoed
鎖で繋ぎ止められたメロディー
A melody chained and held back
もうサヨナラ告げるために
To finally say goodbye
プレイリストから消去しようとして
Trying to delete it from the playlist
でもそれすらもできなくて
But I couldn't even do that
どうせ忘れることはできないから
Since I can't forget it anyway
未練混じり生きていく
I'll keep living with these lingering feelings
せめて次はこの歌を聴く時は
At least, the next time I hear this song
ねぇ 今よりも上手に笑えるように
Hey, I hope I can smile better than I do now
ねぇ 最後まで涙を流さないように
Hey, I hope I won't cry until the very end
ということで、そらちゃんオリジナル曲『未練レコード』を二人でお届けしましたー！
And so, Sora-chan and I performed her original song "Miren Record"!
イエーイ！
Yay!
そらちゃんありがとう！
Thank you, Sora-chan!
こちらこそ、一緒に歌えてとっても、
No, thank you, singing together was really...
ほんと、ほんと、楽しかった！
...really, really fun!
ちょっとまた後で呼ぶね。
I'll call you back later.
本当？
Really?
うん。
Yeah.
やったー！
Hooray!
じゃあまた呼ぶねー。
Well, I'll call you again later.
ありがとう！おめでとう！
Thank you! Congratulations!
はい、ということでね、皆さんね、今日のサムネイルで分かっていると思いますが、
Yes, and so, as you probably know from today's thumbnail,
次のゲストをお呼びしたいと想います。
I'd like to invite the next guest on stage.
行きますよ。
Here we go.
すいちゃーん！
Sui-chaaan!
はーい！イエーイ！
Hi! Yay!
イエーイ！
Yay!
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石、アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいでーす！
It's the diamond in the rough that appeared like a comet, idol VTuber Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃん今日も可愛い！
Sui-chan is cute today too!
今日も可愛い！
Cute today too!
イエーイ！AZKiちゃん誕生日おめでとう！
Yay! Happy birthday, AZKi-chan!
ありがとう！来てくれて嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so glad you came!
イエーイ！嬉しいですよ！それとね、もう一つ
Yay! I'm happy too! And there's one more thing
言いたいことがあります。
I want to say.
何何？
What is it?
ホロライブへようこそー！
Welcome to Hololive!
おおー、そう、移籍してね。
Oh, right, I transferred.
そうなんですよ。初、なんだろうね、ライブをするのが初めてなので。
That's right. It's my first, well, first time performing a live since then.
ね、もう3ヶ月は経ってしまったんですけど。
Right, though it's already been three months.
そうなんですよ。そうなんです。
That's true. That's true.
なんでまあ今日、ちょっとね、そらちゃんとすいちゃんを呼んでライブをしたいと思って
So, I wanted to have a live with Sora-chan and Sui-chan today,
ちょっとオファーをしました。
so I sent them an offer.
待って。なんかさ、もうめっちゃエモい気持ちになっちゃって。
Wait. I'm already feeling so emotional.
1曲目からさ、もうなんかステージがこのホロアリーナになったから。すごいめちゃめちゃ感動してる。
From the very first song, the stage being here in the Holo Arena is making me so moved.
うわぁーって。
Whoa...
崩れ落ちる。
I'm falling apart.
Falling apart.
一般通過の星街さん。
Just a passerby, Hoshimachi-san.
本当にすごい感動しました。
I was really moved.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
はい、すいちゃんがね、来てくれたということで
Yes, since Sui-chan is here,
あの曲を。
let's sing that song.
あれですね。
That one.
そう、あの曲を歌いたいなと思って。
Yes, I want to sing that song.
歌いましょう！
Let's sing it!
行きます。
Let's go.
はい、じゃあ定位置につくぞ。
Alright, let's get into position.
ここだ。
Right here.
ここだ、ここだ、はい。
Here, here, okay.
では、タイトルコール一緒にしれくれますか？
Now, will you do the title call with me?
はい。
Yes.
行きますよ。
Here we go.
せーの！
One, two...!
The Last Frontier!
The Last Frontier
未知の期待 抱え出逢った
Met while carrying unknown expectations
あの日の僕らは
We of that day
そこに沸き上がる何かを
Something welling up inside
言葉にできなくて
Couldn't be put into words
僕ら 気付いた時には 遠く離れてて
By the time we noticed, we were far apart
もう 二度と逢うことないと思っていた
Thinking we would never meet again
でも 聴こえていたよ 君が歌を歌うから
But I could hear you, because you were singing
ずっと
Always
Last Frontier!
孤独な星たちへ 捧げる歌を
A song dedicated to the lonely stars
Last...
一人で最果て 旅立つ歌を
A song for a journey to the end alone
Last...
交わることのない 世界を今迎えるから
Because we're now facing a world that never intersects
最後の一行に
In the final line
君と僕を 出逢う
You and I meet
Whoa whoa...
道は別れ想い描いた
I envisioned a fork in the road
風が冷たくて
The wind was cold
晴れない灰色を街をただ
Just looking out over the city
眺め続けていた
In its unending grey
僕ら何を信じたら
What should we have believed in?
よかったんだろう
I wonder
きっと立ち止まることは
Surely, stopping
諦めることで
Is the same as giving up
でも忘れないように
But so that I don't forget
君に言葉紡ぐから
I'll spin words for you
超えて
Going beyond
The Last Frontier
水平線の先 目指す場所まで
Beyond the horizon, to our destination
The Last Frontierの彼方 辿り着くまで
Until we reach the end of the Last Frontier
ばらばらに砕けた欠片をここに集めたわ
I gathered the scattered fragments here
明日へ
Towards tomorrow
息を
Holding our
止めて
breath
さよならで別の運命が流れ落ちてゆく日に
On the day another fate trickles down with a goodbye
会いに行く
I'm coming to see you
強くこらえた夜明けはいつか終わるこの世界から
From this world where the endured dawn will eventually end
愛を伝えにゆく
I'm going to convey my love
The Last Frontier
君なら行ける
If it's you, you can make it
まだ見たことのない世界へ行ける
You can go to a world you've never seen before
僕は観測する輝き止まぬ星の名を
I observe the name of the star whose light never fails
Remember The Frontier
愛する星たちへ捧げる歌を
A song dedicated to the stars I love
光の最果て 旅立つ歌を
A song for departing to the furthest edge of light
ばらばらに砕けた欠片をここに集めたわ
I gathered the scattered fragments here
明日へ
To tomorrow
帰るから
Because I'm returning
響かせよう 僕ら今を
Let our present moment resonate
歌う
We sing
次はこの曲！
Next is this song!
すいちゃんの、「天球、彗星は夜を跨いで」！
Suichan's "Celestial Sphere, Comets Straddle the Night"!
二人で歌いたいと思います！
We're going to sing it together!
イエーイ！
Yeah!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
灯りがひとつ灯った 灯った
A single light flickered on, flickered on
天を彩った秒が綺麗だ
The seconds that painted the heavens were beautiful
僕の吐いた白い息のように 消してしまえたらな
I wish I could erase it like the white breath I exhaled
押し殺して深く沈んだ
Stifled, it sank deep
泣き声さえ聞こえているから
Because I can even hear the sobbing
君を刺した万目雲 僕の青色で塗り潰して
Overwhelming clouds that pierced you, I'll paint over them with my blue
全部涙になって 星の海の中へ出て行った
It all turned to tears and went out into the sea of stars
果てない闇の中に そっとハを添えたら
If I softly add a breath into the endless darkness
彗星が僕たちの街を飛んだ
A comet flew over our city
誰もいない夜の空を飛んだ
It flew across the empty night sky
不確かに静まった街の中へ
Into the city that had fallen uncertainly silent
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Whose sorrow is it that's raining down?
星はまだ弧を描いて飛んだ
The star still flew, drawing an arc
靄の彼方 姿を離して
Letting go of its form beyond the haze
いつかまた会えるなんて言えなかった
I couldn't say that we'd meet again someday
星が降った朝の街 僕は
In the city where stars fell in the morning, I...
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
黒く澄んだガランドウの空を　尾を引く星が彩るように
Like the trailing stars coloring the clear, black, empty sky
君が刺した不安も苦痛も　僕の青色で塗りつぶして
I'll paint over the anxiety and pain you inflicted with my blue color
君の未来をそっと　星の海に流し込むんだ
Gently pouring your future into the sea of stars
尾を引いたその光が　誰かをまた救うから
Because that trailing light will save someone again
彗星が空をなぞるのなら　この空を全て君にあげる
If a comet traces the sky, I'll give this entire sky to you
言えなかった言葉の尾を引いて　降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう？
Trailing the tail of words left unsaid, whose sadness is it that's raining down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ　街の視線を奪い去るように
The stars flew, drawing another arc, as if to steal away the city's gaze
君とまた会えるなら僕はそっと　星の名前を一つ受け止めよう
If I can meet you again, I'll gently accept the name of a star
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
悲しみが溢れ　澄み渡ること　天球で離ればなれでも
Sadness overflows and clears the air, even if we're apart in the celestial sphere
僕らは繋がっているから
Because we are connected
彗星が空をなぞるのなら　誰もいない夜の空を埋めた
If a comet traces the sky, it filled the empty night sky
不確実を澄ました街の中へ　降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう？
Into the city that cleared away uncertainty, whose sadness is it that's raining down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ　もやのかかった思考を晴らして
The stars flew, drawing another arc, clearing away my hazy thoughts
いつかのまた会えるなんて言えなかった
I couldn't say that we'd meet again someday
僕はもうずっと君の行方を　探してた
I've been searching for your whereabouts all this time
ということで、すいちゃんオリジナル曲、天球、彗星は夜を跨いでを二人でお届けしました！
And so, we performed Suisei's original song, 'Tenkyuu, Suisei wa Yoru wo Mataide' together!
イェーイ！嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
もう本当に、この曲はすいちゃんのことこう、知って、初めて、そう、聞いた時の曲で、めちゃくちゃ、なんかとても思い出深くて。
Really, this was the first song of yours I heard when I first got to know you, Suisei, so it's very meaningful to me.
いや懐かしい！本当に、私はイノナカ入る前とかに、あのね、あのAZラジで紹介したことがあって。
It brings back memories! Actually, before I joined INNK, I introduced it on AZ-Radio.
そうそうそう！前とかにね。もうそこで聞いた曲を絶対にいつか、そのすいちゃんと歌いたいなと思っていて。今日ちょっとこの選曲をしてまいりました。
That's right! A while back. Ever since I heard it then, I've wanted to sing it with you someday. So I chose this song for today.
これはエモいですよ！
This is so emotional!
ありがとう！一緒に歌ってくれて。
Thank you! For singing it with me.
いえいえいえ。
No problem at all.
はい、ということでですね。皆さん、次の曲はゲストみんなで歌いたいと思いますので、そらちゃんをお呼びしたいと思います！そらちゃーん！
Alright, and with that... Everyone, for the next song, I want to sing it with all the guests, so I'd like to call out Sora-chan! Sora-chaaan!
そらちゃーん！
Sora-chaaan!
すごかったー！
That was amazing!
一発通過のそら。
First-try Sora.
一発通過のそらが来たよ！
First-try Sora is here!
いや、素晴らしかったなー。
Wow, that was wonderful.
いやなんかね、ちょっと袖にいるね、そらちゃん見えたんですけど、もうなんか、ううってきてた。
Yeah, I could see Sora-chan in the wings, and she looked really moved.
コーラスもめっちゃ良かった！
The chorus was so good too!
えー、ありがとう。
Aw, thank you.
めっちゃ良かった。もうすいちゃんも、パッパッパッパッパラッパってした。
It was so good. Suisei, too, did that 'pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa' part.
混じりたかった？
Did you want to join in?
混じりたかった。あの、イケメンなすいちゃんでパッパッパッパッパラッパって。
I wanted to join in. With cool Suisei doing 'pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa'.
三層にしようかな？
Maybe I should make it three layers?
三層にしよっか？
Should we make it three layers?
急に現れてやろうかなって。
I was thinking of just appearing suddenly.
あ、またなの！？みたいな。
Oh, again!? Something like that.
はい、ということでですね、今日は三人が揃ったので、AZKiのオリジナル曲を一緒に、今日歌ってもらいたいと思います！
Alright, and since all three of us are here today, I'd like for us to sing one of my original songs together!
イェーイ！
Yay!
準備はいいですか？
Are you ready?
はい！
Yes!
それではいきたいと思います。次の曲聴いてください、Intersection。
Alright, here we go. Please listen to the next song, Intersection.
一緒に盛り上がっていきましょう！まずはそらちゃん！
Let's all get hyped together! First up, Sora-chan!
溢れたいな　赤白急送　はまる　君の交差点
I want to overflow, Red White Express, getting stuck in your intersection
1, 2!
変わりたいな　気持ちもっと　イエロー　ちょい危ないで
I want to change, my feelings more, yellow, it's a bit dangerous
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ネオン眩しい...夜...
The neon is dazzling... Night...
いくら満たされても
No matter how fulfilled I feel
いくら模索り合っても
No matter how much we search for each other
薄暗いドアの向こう側
Beyond the dim door
コレクションした
I searched for
君の体温を 探したわ
your body heat I had collected
アルコールで踏みつけたフロア
On the floor trodden with alcohol
この鼓動が 調和するように
Hoping this heartbeat will harmonize
「気にしないで」なんて言わないで
Don't say "don't worry about it"
本当はいつも正直じゃないけど
Though I'm never truly honest
「気が付いてよ」なんて言えなくて
I can't even say "notice me"
嘘ばかり...
Nothing but lies...
溺れたいな I gotcha ぎゅっと
I want to drown, I gotcha tight
嵌る君の交差点
At your intersection, I'm stuck
変わりたいな 気持ちもっと
I want to change my feelings more
ブルー飲み干す体
My body drinking up the blue
認めたいな I wanna close to
I want to admit it, I wanna be close to
かなりギリの通過点
A passing point quite on the edge
変わりたいな 気持ちもっと
I want to change my feelings more
イエロー躊躇わないで
Don't hesitate at the yellow
ラップパート行くぞ、すいちゃん、そら！
Here comes the rap part, Sui-chan, Sora!
点滅と減滅の間 永遠と快楽の狭間
Between blinking and fading, between eternity and pleasure
行方も知れず 過ぎ合う White 黒く塗り潰す日常
Passing each other aimlessly, White painting over daily life in black
境界ばかり染めてどうした そんなに急かさんなよ
What's with only dyeing the boundaries? Don't rush me so much
クラクラ ステップ クラクラ 鳴り響いた ララバイ
Dizzy steps, dizzy, a resonating lullaby
ダラリクラリも いいじゃないかと
Isn't it okay to just lounge around?
消えない染みと 言い訳吐いて
Spitting out excuses with permanent stains
耳の奥底で 繰り返す
Repeating in the depths of my ears
イヤフォンで聴き飽きた曲が
A song I've grown tired of in my earphones
この日常と 交差するように
Crosses over with this daily life
「気にしないで」なんて言わないで
Don't say "don't worry about it"
本当はいつも正直じゃないけど
Though I'm never truly honest
「気が付いてよ」なんて言えなくて
I can't even say "notice me"
嘘ばかり...
Nothing but lies...
溺れたいな I gotcha ぎゅっと
I want to drown, I gotcha tight
嵌る君の交差点
At your intersection, I'm stuck
変わりたいな 気持ちもっと
I want to change my feelings more
ブルー飲み干す体
My body drinking up the blue
認めたいな I wanna close to
I want to admit it, I wanna be close to
かなりギリの通過点
A passing point quite on the edge
変わりたいな 気持ちもっと
I want to change my feelings more
イエロー躊躇わないで
Don't hesitate at the yellow
二人ともありがとう！
Thank you both so much!
ということで、AZKiオリジナル曲『Intersection』を3人でお届けしました！
So, the three of us performed AZKi's original song, "Intersection"!
わーい！この曲大好き！嬉しい！
Yay! I love this song! I'm so happy!
ありがとう！本当に本当に、今日は3人とこうやってライブをすることができて、
Thank you! Truly, I'm so incredibly happy to be able to perform live
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです。
with the three of us today.
今日はそらさん、どうでしたか？じゃあ、そらちゃんどうでしたか？今日は。
Sora-san, how was it for you today? So, Sora-chan, how was today?
いやもうなんかね、AZKiちゃんの誕生日ってことで、今日はね、すごいね、気合を入れて頑張りました。
Well, since it's AZKi-chan's birthday, I put in a lot of effort and worked really hard today.
嬉しい！そう、すごいなんか、ちょっと『Intersection』ね、知らなくて、
I'm so glad! Yeah, you didn't know "Intersection" at first,
ですごい頑張って覚えてきてくれて、めちゃくちゃ嬉しかった。
so I was really happy that you worked so hard to learn it.
めちゃくちゃラップ緊張した...
I was so nervous about the rap...
めちゃくちゃラップパートだと思って、すごく緊張したんですけど、一生懸命歌わせていただきました。
I thought, "It's a huge rap part!", so I was really nervous, but I gave it my all.
ありがとう、ありがとうございました。よかったー、楽しかったです。
Thank you, thank you so much. I'm glad, it was fun.
AZKi、おめでとう！おめでとー！
Congratulations, AZKi!
ありがとう！そして、すいちゃんどうでしたか？今日は。
Thank you! And how about you, Sui-chan? How was it today?
いや、すいちゃんはね、今日の1曲目と2曲目を見て、
Well, watching today's first and second songs,
うわあ、そうだ、AZKiちゃんと会ったのは、こんな時だった！
I was like, "Wow, that's right, this is what it was like when I first met AZKi-chan!"
って思ってさ、このさ、なんかさ、昔の小さな事務所時代を思い出しちゃった。
I was thinking about that and it reminded me of the old days back at our small office.
そうだね。ね、もう小さな部屋でさ、なんか、一緒に話したりとか。
You're right. In that tiny room, just chatting together.
思い出しちゃいました。
It brings back memories.
改めてね、お誕生日とホロライブ加入と、まあこれからね、色々あると思いますけど、
Once again, happy birthday and welcome to Hololive. I'm sure there's a lot ahead,
頑張っていただきたいなと思います！
but I'll be rooting for you!
ありがとう！おめでとう！
Thank you! Congratulations!
そらちゃん、今日は一日ありがとうございました！
Sora-chan, thank you so much for today!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
では、ここでお別れになりますが、また、やろうねライブ！
We have to say goodbye now, but let's do another live concert again!
やろう！やろう！
Let's do it!
じゃあ、またね！お祝いしてくれてありがとう！
See you later! Thank you for celebrating with me!
ばいばーい！おめでとう！
Bye-bye! Congratulations!
行くぞ、そらちゃん！ぬん！ぬん！
Here we go, Sora-chan! Nun! Nun!
ぬん、元気のいいぬんが聞こえてきましたが。
I heard some very energetic "nun"s there.
はい、そろそろ誕生祭ライブも終盤となりました。
Yes, we're nearing the end of the birthday live concert.
皆さんにここで、重大発表を、伝えたいことがありますので、
I have an important announcement to share with everyone here,
ここで発表していきたいと思います。
so I'd like to announce it now.
それでは、いきます。こちらです！
So, here it is!
AZKi 4ヶ月連続デジタルシングル、リリース決定！！
AZKi's release of 4 consecutive digital singles is confirmed!!
AZKi 4ヶ月連続デジタルシングル リリース決定いたしました！
AZKi's 4-month consecutive digital single release is confirmed!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
第1弾は『Afterglow』
The first one is "Afterglow".
2022年7月3日 24:00より配信開始いたします。
Streaming starts on July 3rd, 2022, at midnight.
そして、こちらの新曲MVが、本日この後22時...
And the music video for this new song will be released today at 10:00...
...15分にプレミア公開されます。
...15 PM for its premiere.
デジタル配信とMV、併せてぜひ見て、聴いてくれたら...
I hope you'll check out both the digital release and the MV...
...嬉しいです。
...and listen to it.
はい。
Alright.
ということで、本日はですね、こちらの新曲を...
So, today, I'm going to...
...今ここ、今ここでですね、披露しようと思います。
...perform this new song right here, right now.
その前に、お水飲んでいいですか？
Before that, may I have some water?
お水を飲んで。
Let me get some water.
行きたいと思います。
Let's get started.
それでは、皆さん、新曲聴いてください。
Now, everyone, please listen to the new song.
Afterglow。
Afterglow.
もう行かなくちゃいけない
I have to go now
永く遠い路の終わり
At the end of a long, distant road
静かに眠ったおでこを合わせて
Placing our foreheads together as you sleep peacefully
深く息をした
I took a deep breath
見上げた先には赤い空
I looked up to see a crimson sky
きっと同じ空を見ているのかな
I wonder if you're looking at the same sky too
胸に残るあなたの あなたの あなたの声が今
Deep in my chest, your, your, your voice is now...
夢に落ちて 夢で覚める
...falling into a dream, waking up in a dream
あなたの あなたの あなたの記憶今
Your, your, your memories now...
私を置いてゆく
...are leaving me behind
ほら幸せなことは
Look, the happy things...
すぐに消えてしまうようで
...seem to vanish in an instant
あんなに好きだった景色も音楽も
The scenery and music I loved so much...
色褪せてしまった
...have all faded away
今を生きていくこと
To live in the present
一人ひたすら走ること
To run alone with all my might
私という存在は脆くて
My existence is so fragile
その足動かない
And my feet won't move
見上げた先には灰の空
I looked up to see a gray sky
ちゃんと色を取り戻せるように
So that I can truly regain the colors
世界の真ん中
In the center of the world
あなたの あなたの あなたの声が今
Your, your, your voice is now...
こだましている
...echoing
世界のどこか あなたの あなたの あなたの欠片今
Somewhere in the world, your, your, your fragments now...
私は探している
...I am searching for them
胸に残るあなたの あなたの あなたの声が今
Deep in my chest, your, your, your voice is now...
空に溶けていく
...melting into the sky
夢で覚める あなたの あなたの あなたの記憶今
Waking up in a dream, your, your, your memories now...
私を連れて行く
...are taking me away
きっと良かった
It must have been for the best
これで最後
This is the end
もう行かなくちゃ
I have to go now
夢が終わる
The dream ends.
ということで新曲、afterglowお聞きいただきました。
And so, you've just heard my new song, "afterglow."
こちらの新曲はAZKiが作詞作曲しております。
I wrote the lyrics and composed this new song myself.
作曲は代次郎さんと一緒に、そして代次郎さんに編曲していただきました。
I composed it together with Daijiro-san, and he also did the arrangement.
いかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you like it?
ね、私のいる世界もみんなの世界もどんどんね、こう時間の流れとともに変わっていっていると思うんですけど、
You know, both my world and yours are constantly changing with the flow of time...
まあなんかその中で、なんか名残惜しかったこととか、なんかそういうことがたくさんあって、
and in that, there are many things that I felt reluctant to let go of...
でもそれにこう別れを告げなきゃいけない、そんなことをこの曲に込めました。
but we have to say goodbye to them anyway. I put those feelings into this song.
たくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you listen to it a lot.
はい、そしてここで告知！二つ目あります！
All right, and now for an announcement! I have a second one!
皆さんお待たせいたしました！AZKi誕生日グッズが出ます！こちらです！
Thank you for waiting, everyone! AZKi birthday goods are coming out! Here they are!
ホロライブに移籍してから初めてのグッズ、初めての直筆サインも書きます！
These are my first goods since moving to Hololive, and I'll also be doing hand-signed items for the first time!
ぜひ手に入れてください。内容は、
Please be sure to get them. The contents are...
B2タペストリー、
A B2 tapestry...
そしてランダムアクリルキーホルダー、
and random acrylic keychains...
はい、タンブラー、
a tumbler...
そしてコースター！
and a coaster!
シチュエーションボイスがついてフルセットで、
Plus a situation voice, all in a full set!
直筆サイン入りポストカードが数量限定になりますので、
The hand-signed postcards are limited in quantity...
ぜひお早めに購入してください。
so please purchase yours early.
フルセット、サインがない方も、複製サイン入りポストカードを箔押しで入れておりますので、
And even the full set without the hand-signature comes with a foil-stamped replica signature postcard...
どうぞよろしくお願いします。
so please look forward to it.
販売開始はこのあと22時からとなっております。よろしくお願いします。
Sales will start at 22:00 tonight. Thank you!
はい、ということで早いものでライブも残り一曲となりました。
All right, time flies and we're already down to the last song of the live.
ちょっと最後の挨拶に、ちょっと皆さんから私から、いろいろお伝えしたいなと思います。
For my final greeting, I'd like to share a few things with all of you.
去年、12月にイノナカミュージック終了の発表してですね、
In December last year, the end of INoNaKa Music was announced...
今年4月にホロライブに移籍してから、もう今日この誕生日ライブを迎えるまで、たくさんのことがありまして、
and since moving to Hololive in April, a lot has happened leading up to today's birthday live.
AZKiなりにこう必死に頑張ってきました。
I've been working as hard as I can in my own way.
イノナカミュージック終了にあたってはですね、AZKiの活動辞めるべきかと考えたり、
When INoNaKa Music ended, I wondered if I should stop my activities as AZKi...
卒業することが本当は綺麗な終わりだったかもしれないと、何度も思ったことがありました。
and I often thought that graduating might have been the "proper" way to end things.
今でもどこかでそうしたほうがよかったんじゃないかなと思うことがあります。
Even now, a part of me sometimes wonders if that would have been better.
でも開拓者のみんながいてくれて、ホロライブのみんながいてくれて、
But because all the Pioneers and everyone at Hololive were there for me...
今のAZKiがあり今日このステージに立つことができています。
I am who I am today and I'm able to stand on this stage.
今日こうやって4回目の誕生日を一緒に迎えてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for celebrating my fourth birthday with me today.
本当にAZKiは本当にみんながいなければ、ここにいませんでした。
Truly, if it wasn't for all of you, AZKi wouldn't be here.
AZKiはAZKiの世界を続けてこれませんでした。
I wouldn't have been able to continue the world of AZKi.
私は本当にこの世界が大好きです。
I really love this world.
歌うことも大好きです。
And I love singing too.
これからも、どんな形であれ、作り上げてきた音楽とか作品とかを大切にして活動していきたいと思っています。
From now on, in whatever form it takes, I want to continue my activities while cherishing the music and works I've created.
これからも応援してくれますか？
Will you continue to support me?
これからも、どうぞよろしくお願いします。
I look forward to your continued support.
いつもみんなありがとう。
Thank you as always, everyone.
それでは今日最後の曲、聴いてください。いのち。
And now, please listen to the last song of the day: "Life" (Inochi).
いのち / 作詞・作曲・編曲：瀬名航
Life / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Wataru Sena
息をしている
I am breathing.
君は生きている
You are alive.
当然のことだね
It's only natural...
誰も疑わないの
no one doubts it.
息をしている
You look as if...
様に見えている
you're breathing.
生の裏側
On the flip side of life...
私にとっての何か
it's something for me.
鼓動がドクトクしている
My heart is thumping.
叩かれても腐らずに
Without rotting even if beaten...
此処で歌うよ
I'll sing here.
ボタン一つのいのち
A life of a single button.
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the end?
消えてしまいそうなの
I feel like I'm about to disappear.
わかってよ わかってよ ねえ
Understand me, understand me, hey.
本当のところなの
It's the truth.
恋慕わしくは違うでしょう
“To be beloved” is wrong, isn't it?
君が忘れちゃったら
If you forget...
私は居なくなるの
I will be gone.
いのちのような夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream like a life.
またね バイバイ
See you later, bye bye.
だから生きている
So I'm alive
自己証明を
Self-proof
欲しがって、欲しがっているんだ
I'm wanting, wanting it
音が止まって
The sound stops
動かなくなって
And becomes motionless
そんな私を
That kind of me
君は笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll smile at
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heart is thumping
嫌われても腐らずに
Without rotting even if I'm hated
此処で歌うよ
I'll sing here
気分次第に
Depending on my mood
いのち
Life
最後まで私のこと見届けてくれんの？
Will you see me through to the end?
覚めてしまいそうなの
I feel like I'm about to wake up
わかってよ　わかってよ　ねえ
Understand, understand, hey
声が聞こえるんだよ
I can hear a voice
白か黒いならまだマシじゃんか
It would be better if it were just black or white
君が忘れちゃったら私は居なくなるの
If you forget me, I'll disappear
命のような夢を見ているよ
I'm having a dream that's like a life
またねバイバイ
See you again, bye-bye
塞ぎ込んだあの日を
Those days when I was feeling down
軽く弄らないで
Don't tease me lightly
やめて
Stop it
それが生きる糧になるから
Because that becomes the fuel for living
大丈夫　ずっと
It's okay, always
私は歌い続けるから
Because I will continue to sing
最後まで私は生きているか分かんないけど
I don't know if I'll be alive until the end
君がくれた言葉は確かに残ってる
But the words you gave me certainly remain
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれんの？
Will you remember me until the end?
いつか死んでしまうのか
Whether I will die someday
分かんない　分かんないよ　ねえ
I don't know, I don't know, hey
痛いくらい気持ちがシンクロする時もあるけど
There are times when our feelings synchronize to the point of pain
君が忘れちゃったら私は居なくなるの
If you forget me, I'll disappear
命のような夢を見ているよ
I'm having a dream that's like a life
またねバイバイ
See you again, bye-bye
いつも応援してくれてありがとう♡
Thank you for always supporting me ♡
これからも一緒に世界をつくっていこうね。
Let's continue to create the world together.
2022.07.03 AZKi ♡